Just beyond your dreams lives a secret world. Where every tree is a home. Every
sound is a song. And humans only exist in fairy tales. Until now...
FernGully: The Last Rainforest is a family, fantasy,
animation film directed by Bill Kroyer.
When a sprite named Crysta shrinks a human boy, Zak, down to her size, he vows to help the magical fairy folk stop
a greedy logging company from destroying their home: the pristine rainforest known as FernGully.
Zak and his new friends fight to defend FernGully from lumberjacks — and the vengeful
spirit they accidentally unleash after chopping down a magic tree.
Crysta (voice), played by Samantha Mathis.
Zak Young (voice), played by Jonathan Ward.
Pips (voice), played by Christian Slater.
Batty Koda (voice), played by Robin Williams.
Hexxus (voice), played by Tim Curry.
Magi Lune (voice), played by Grace Zabriskie.
FernGully: The Last Rainforest is a 1992 animated musical fantasy film
directed by Bill Kroyer in his feature directorial debut.
Scripted by Jim Cox and adapted from the "FernGully" stories by Diana Young, the film is an Australian and American venture
produced by Kroyer Films, Inc., Youngheart Productions, and FAI Films, and distributed by 20th Century Fox.
It stars the voices of Samantha Mathis, Christian Slater, Jonathan
Ward, Robin Williams, Tim Curry, and Grace Zabriskie.
The film is set in an Australian rainforest inhabited by fairies, including Crysta, who
accidentally shrinks a young logger named Zak to the size of a fairy.
Together, they rally the fairies and the animals of the rainforest to protect their
home from the loggers and Hexxus, a malevolent pollution entity.
Wayne Young, the film's producer, said that the film was "blatantly
environmental", although he made an effort to avoid "preaching".
FernGully was released in North America on April 10, 1992, to mainly positive reviews, and was generally
considered a moderate financial success at both the box office and in home video sales.
In 1998, it was followed by a direct-to-video sequel, FernGully 2: The Magical
Rescue, although none of the original voice cast reprised their roles.
The film explores themes of pollution, fairy, musical, bat, environment.